Tiffany Timbric Broomfield, Colorado 80023

Summary

Senior enterprise backend software developer passionate about code, both functional and imperative: I write mission-critical system backends across many domains, financial, transportation, telecommunications, e-commerce, defense, etc. I started at Sun Microsystems, Inc. assisting their top clients in implementation of JEE patterns with code quality. More recently I used AWS, Serverless, Spring, Network Bulkheads, Java Optional, Reactive eXtensions, NoSQL to design and author reliable Java systems deployed on AWS.

Skills / Experience

Java, Kotlin, Scala, Bash + Linux (Postman, Curl, jq, tmux), Spring Boot (REST, JSON), AWS (S3, SQS, Lambda, Pipelines, EC2), Reactive eXtensions (RxJava), Bulkheads (Hystrix), JEE Design Patterns, Microservices, ETL, SQL (Oracle, PostgreSQL, Maria/MySQL), NoSQL (Cassandra, Mongo), Messaging (JMS, SQS, Rabbit, Active MQ), TDD (JUnit, Mockito, Wiremock, Gerkin, Cucumber), Encryption (SSH, H2-MAC, NTRU, XOR), RPC TCP UDP Networking (Wireshark, Protobuf, Finagle, Wireshark, RMI, CORBA), Git, BDD, DDD, GitHub, Bitbucket, Nexus, Artifactory, Multi-factor Auth (OAUTH), Single Sign On, OSGi, Jenkins, Bamboo, Atlassian Tools, ...

Software Architecture

The C4 Model – Context, Containers, Components, Code: https://c4model.com

Code Examples

- Finite State Machine: https://github.com/chadwickboggs/fsm
- Cryptography: https://github.com/chadwickboggs/crypto
- Spring Boot: https://github.com/chadwickboggs/xchange

Education, Certifications, Patents

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, University of Colorado, 1998
- Sun Certified Java Developer, Sun Certified Java Programmer
- AWS Certified Developer (in progress)
- Patent: #6907423 (Search engine interface and method of controlling client searches)
- Electrical Engineering, U.S.M.A. at West Point (attended)

Professional Experience

Amtrak, Denver, CO

2/2023 - 4/2024

Senior Software Developer

- Primary code author (30k+ lines of code) of their AWS rewrite of their entire outbound email system for customer purchases including trip information and sales receipts. Sales receipts and trip information listings for all Amtrak trips, with add-ons, and purchase types, across all Amtrak stations, passenger classes, and third-party carriers.
- Features included the handling of and processing scale for all Amtrak customer purchases, the publishing of business metric, system metric for observability, error / failure alerting, meaningful trace, debug, info, warn, and error logging with security and PII protection.
- Technologies included AWS (Cloud Formation, Lambda, Event Bridge, SQS, S3), immutables.org Java Beans, REST, JSON + FasterXML Jackson, HttpClient, environment specific configuration, environment variables, Java 11, Maven.

GHX, Louisville, CO 6/2022 – 1/2023

Senior Software Engineer

- Lead team authoring software connecting hospital ERP and medical equipment purchasing systems to GHX.
- Used AWS EC2, SQS, S3, and Lambdas, Java, Oracle.
- Web Services, FTP, sFTP, HTTP(S), JSON serialization/deserialization, SQL.
- Deployed in 100's of customer data centers, two-week release cadence w/ prod deploys.

PayPal, Denver, CO 2/2020 – 5/2022

Software Developer

- Implemented direct deposit signup services in Spring Boot.
- Implemented account bank migrations, bank change, for all PayPal accounts in Spring Batch.
- Maintained and implemented feature enhancements to a batch merchant report generation system.

Arris/Commscope, Denver, CO

Software Engineer

- · Updated the video catalog and merchandising backend originally authored by Motorola for Bouygues Telecom,
- Used Java EE, WildFly, GlassFish, WebSphere, REST, Wiremock, Mockito, Postman, Wireshark.

Comcast, Corp., Denver CO

1/2018 - 4/2018

1/2019 - 10/2019

Software Engineer

Updated one Java system to Docker/Kubernetes, Java 11, Cucumber, Reactive Extensions, Git.

Charter Communications, Denver, CO

1/2016 - 12/2017

- Software Engineer,
 - Maintained 100+ Java micro-services, added new micro-services all in Amazon Web Services.
 - Used Linux, Netflix OSS, Cassandra NoSQL, Reactive Extensions, Java 8, SQS, SNS, S3, EC2, Active MQ, Mongo, Git, Spring.

Comcast, Corp., Denver, CO

9/2014 - 2/2015

Software Engineer,

Designed and built "RxJDBC," a Reactive Extension, RabbitMQ Message Oriented Middleware (MOM) front to an Oracle database as part of the Resiliency Project, Java, Git.

Tendril, Inc., Boulder, CO

2/2014 - 5/2014

Software Engineer

- Back-end dev-ops programmer on SOA Finagle+Protobuf+Cloud Java/Scala micro-services.
- Used Atlassian, Cucumber BDD, PostgreSQL, Hadoop, Hibernate, Scala, Intelli-J IDEA, Git.

JDA Software Group, Inc. Denver, CO

2/2010 - 12/2013

Senior Software Engineer

- Project Lead for integration of iOS, Android mobile task system with legacy web-based system
- Tasks roughly is E-mail messages enhanced for distributing and tracking business actions.
- Customers include Fortune-500 companies. Scalability, performance was significant.
- Technologies: OSGi, Gradle, Git, and SQL Server, Git, Mercurial, Subversion, CVS.
- Extended and maintained legacy J2EE web-based task management system.

Independent Consultant, Denver, CO

1/2008 - 12/2009

Software Developer

- Extended and maintained a JEE merchandise inventory system
- Used MySQL DB, Java, Spring.
- Customers included Bell South, e-Bay, Frontier Airlines, AmDocs, Etilize, Skyway

Evolution Hosting, Inc. Louisville, CO

2/2007 - 12/2007

Chief Operation Officer

- Viasest data center Linux servers for J2EE applications with Java management software.
- Customers included Crocks, Wells Fargo, Hunter Douglass, among others.
- Used J2EE, Linux, VMware, Xen (Linux virtual machines), Amazon Web Services, MySQL

Independent Consultant, Denver, CO

2/2004 - 1/2007

Software Developer

- Created NIO client with could reach 100 Mb/s scale message rates.
- Created new web sites, Java.
- Consulted at eBay, Frontier Airlines, Bell South, Skyway representing Sun Microsystems, Inc.

Packexpo, Inc. Fairfax, VA **Software Architect**

2/2002 - 2/2004

- Created a reporting system for packaging advertising services.
- Maintained packaging advertising web site.

• Technologies: J-Boss, Linux, MySQL, Intelli-J, BeanShell, JSP, Lzop'ed data stream for large DB backups over NFS mounts, Java, Groovy.

Sun Microsystems, Inc. Broomfield, CO Java Consulting,

2/1999 - 1/2002

- Represented Sun for RUP, UP, SunTone, OOA&D mentoring and J2EE coding, Java, SCCS, Teamware, RCS, Solaris, Java.
- Consulted at Citigroup, Vanguard Fiduciary Trust, Credit Suisse.
- · Performed an Architecture Assessment recommending SOA and JEE which later was followed as advised.

Sun Microsystems, Inc. Broomfield, CO Java Developer

4/1998 - 1/1999

- Created web-based and Swing computer assisted training systems.
- Improved the performance of our custom pseudo-recursive-descent parser template engine by adding caching of parser
- results and by altering the parsing algorithm.